Register of the Sidney Hook papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1917-1990 (Boxes 31-101)
  - "Justice for All: Preference for Some? The Case Against," Bell Telephone Magazine, Autumn Printed copy and letter, 1978. (Folder 18)
  - "Home Truths," Commentary, Sept. 1978. Review of Yvonne Kapp, Eleanor Marx. Printed copy, and letter by Murray Povzea (Folder 19)
  - Letter to the editor, Contemporary Sociology, Sept. 1978. Relates to a review by Jerome H. Skolnick of Ernest van den Haag's book Punishing Criminals. Printed copy, typescript and printed copies of comments by Skolnick, Van den Haag and Hans Toch, and letter (Folder 20)
  - "The Triumph of Racism?" Freedom at Issue, Printed copy, Sept.-Oct. 1978. (Folder 21)
  - "The True Meaning of the Pumpkin," Speech, Pumpkin Papers Irregulars meeting, San Francisco. Printed copy, program, and letters by Paul Seabury, 1978-1979, Oct. 31, 1978. (Folder 22)
  - "Solzhenitsyn and Secular Humanism: A Response," Humanist, Reply to a Harvard University commencement address given by Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn. Printed copy, printed copy of Solzhenitsyn's speech, and letters, 1978-1979, Nov.-Dec. 1978. (Folder 23)
  - "The Conceptual Structure of Power: An Overview," in Donald W. Harward, ed., Power: Its Nature, Its Use, and Its Limits, 1979. Typescript, proofs, and correspondence with Harward and others, 1978-1979 (Folder 24)
  - Eulogy for Rose Zinkin, Holograph, 1979. (Folder 25)
  - "John Dewey: A Hundred Years Later," Typescript, 1979. (Folder 26)
  - "Marxism and Liberty," Dialogue, Printed copy, Winter 1979. (Folder 27)
  - "Anti-Semitism in the Academy: Some Pages of the Past," Midstream, Galleys, printed copy, and correspondence with Arthur P. Davis, Meyer Schapiro and others, 1976-1979, Jan. 1979. (Folder 28)
  - "David Caute's Fable of 'Fear and Terror,'" Encounter, Jan. 1979. Review of David Caute, The Great Fear: The Anti- Communist Purge under Truman and Eisenhower. Holograph notes, galleys, printed copy, and letter (Folder 29)
  - "Social Democracy Means Human Freedom: A Response to the Conservatives," New America, Printed copies, Jan. 1979. (Folder 30)
  - "'A Tale of Mystery - and Detection,'" Encounter, Reply to comments by Eric Jacobs and Margaret Stern on Hook's review "The Case of Alger Hiss: A Historian's Verdict." Holograph, typescript, printed copy, and printed copies of comments by Jacobs, Stern and Allen Weinstein, 1979, March 1979. (Folder 31)
  - "Solzhenitsyn and Western Freedom: How Serious a Challenge?" Speech, Issues in Liberal Education Conference, University of Oklahoma, Norman. Typescript, galleys, printed copy, program, and letters, 1979-1981, March 28, 1979. (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Relates to comments by Donald Meiklejohn on liberty of speech. Typescript, and printed copy of Meiklejohn's comments, April 4, 1979 (Folder 2)
  - "Alternatives to Collective Bargaining," Speech, National Center for the Study of Collective Bargaining in Higher Education, New York City. Typescript, printed copy, and program, April 24, 1979. (Folder 3)
  - "Ideology of the Labor Movement," Speech, Los Angeles Trade-Technical College. Notes and announcement, April 26, 1979. (Folder 4)
  - "Cosmology and Ethics," New Republic, Letter to the editor. Printed copy, May 5, 1979. (Folder 5)
  - "Hook vs. Wills," May 21, 1979, Time. Relates to freedom of ideas. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "Political Wish-Thinking and the Eurocommunist Myth," Policy Review, Summer 1979. Review of Roy Godson and Stephen Haseler, Eurocommunism: Implications for East and West. Holograph, printed copy, and letters (Folder 7)
  - "Remembering Max Eastman," American Scholar, Summer 1979. Review of William L. O'Neill, The Last Romantic: A Life of Max Eastman. Printed copy, contract, and correspondence with O'Neill, Lewis Feuer and Jeffrey Hart, 1979-1981 (Folder 8)
  - Letter to the editor, Russian Review, July 1979. Relates to a review by Andrzej Korbonski of J. K. Zawodny's book Nothing but Honour. Typescript, printed copy, and letters by Zawodny (Folder 9)
  - "Renquist-Burger [sic] Dissent on Weber," Measure, Printed copy, Fall 1979. (Folder 10)
  - "The Weber Case," Commentary, (co-author with Miro Todorovich). Letter to the editor relating to affirmative action programs and the Committee on Academic Nondiscrimination and Integrity. Printed copy, Sept. 1979 (Folder 11)
  - "The Vulnerabilities of Communism," Speech, International Freedoms Conference, Philadelphia. Typescripts, Oct. 26, 1979. (Folder 12)
  - "How to Define the Public Good," Speech, Symposium on the Perplexed Policymaker, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Notes, program, and miscellanea, Nov. 20, 1979. (Folder 13)
  - "Rebuff to Jane Fonda Logical," Dallas Morning News, Typescript and printed copy, Nov. 23, 1979. (Folder 14)
  - "Trotsky: The Prophet Who Failed," New America, Typescript, galleys, printed copies, and letters, 1979-1980, Dec. 1979. (Folder 15)
  - "Karl Marx (1818-1883)," in New Book of Knowledge, Typescript and letter, 1979, 1980. (Folder 16)
  - Philosophy and Public Policy, 1980. Reviews, contract, press release, printed excerpts, miscellany, and correspondence with Roy Godson, David Sidorsky and others, 1977-1982 (Folder 17)
  - Introduction to James H. Wentzel, Countdown 1984: A Review of Federal Government "Minority" Group Preference in Small Business and Public Works Programs (pamphlet), Holograph, typescript copy of Wentzel's study, printed copy, and letters from Wentzel and another, 1979, Jan. 1980. (Folder 18)
  - "Liberalism and the Jews," Commentary, Symposium contribution. Typescript, galleys, printed copy, and correspondence, 1979-1980, Jan. 1980. (Folder 19)
  - "Memories of John Dewey Days: An Autobiographical Fragment," [St. John's] College, Galleys, printed copy, and letter, 1979, Jan. 1980. (Folder 20)
  - Letter to the editor, Commentary, (date written). Relates to comments by Daniel Bell on liberalism. Typescript, and letters to Bell and Norman Podhoretz, 1980, Jan. 8, 1980 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - "The Soviet Britannica: An Intellectual Obscenity," Midstream, Holograph, galleys, printed copy, clipping, and letter, 1979, Feb. 1980. (Folder 2)
  - "Three Intellectual Women," (date written). Primarily relates to Diana Trilling, but planned to include Mary McCarthy and Hannah Arendt. Typescript fragment, Feb. 6, 1980 (Folder 3)
  - "The 'Radical' Tilt against Academic Freedom," Measure, Printed copy, and letters by Milton Friedman and another, 1980, Spring 1980. (Folder 4)
  - "Spectral Marxism," American Scholar, Spring 1980. Review of Leszek Kolakowski, Main Currents of Marxism. Typescript, proof, printed copy, contract, and letters by Burnett Bolloten and others, 1979-1980 (Folder 5)
  - "Textbook Detente with Soviets: Just Another Illusion?" Kansas City Star, Typescript and printed copy, April 6, 1980. (Folder 6)
  - "Isaiah Berlin's Enlightenment," Commentary, May 1980. Review of Isaiah Berlin, Against the Current. Typescript, galleys, notes, proof copy of Berlin's book, printed copy, printed copy of reviews by Jonathan Lieberson and Sidney Morgenbesser, and letters by Berlin and others (Folder 7)
  - "The Institute for Social Research: Addendum," Survey, Typescript, printed copy, galleys of Lewis Feuer's "The Frankfurt Marxists and the Columbia Liberals," and letters by Feuer and Meyer Schapiro, 1980-1981, Summer 1980. (Folder 8)
  - Letter to the editor, Commentary, Relates to comments by Robert Gordis on Hook's article "Isaiah Berlin's Enlightenment." Typescript, typescript copy of Gordis' comments, and letter by Gordis, 1980, July 1980. (Folder 9)
  - "Marx for All Seasons," Commentary, July 1980. Review of Robert L. Heilbroner, Marxism: For and Against. Typescript and printed copy (Folder 10)
  - "Bertrand Russell's Reserve," Midstream, Reply to comments by Harry Ruja on Hook's review "Bertrand Russell the Man." Typescript, Aug.-Sept. 1980. (Folder 11)
  - "Disremembering the Thirties," American Scholar, Autumn 1980. Review of Malcolm Cowley, The Dream of the Golden Mountain: Remembering the Thirties. Typescript, printed copy, and letters (Folder 12)
  - "Academic Freedom in Jeopardy: Time to Strike the Alarm Bell," Measure (supplement), Printed copy, Sept. 1980. (Folder 13)
  - Review of Norman Podhoretz, The Present Danger, American Spectator, Printed copy, and correspondence with Podhoretz and others, 1980-1981, Sept. 1980. (Folder 14)
  - "Selzer and Academic Freedom," Typescript, Sept. 1980. (Folder 15)
  - "Reflections on Tenure and Confidentiality," Measure, Printed copy, Oct. 1980. (Folder 16)
  - "Misread 'Secular Humanist Declaration,'" New York Times, (co-author with Paul Kurtz). Letter to the editor relating to comments by Samuel A. Turk on "A Secular Humanist Declaration." Printed copy, printed comments by Robert J. Farrell, and letter by Milton R. Konvitz, 1980, Nov. 7, 1980 (Folder 17)
  - "Books for Christmas," American Spectator, Short contribution. Printed copy, Dec. 1980. (Folder 18)
  - "Call to Conscience," New York Times, (co- signer with others). Political advertisement relating to the United Nations and Israel. Printed copy, Dec. 14, 1980 (Folder 19)
  - "Authoritarian or Totalitarian: What Difference?" Typescripts, 1981. (Folder 20)
  - "Science and Civilization," Speech written for Ronald Reagan or George Bush relating to Andrei Sakharov (not given). Holograph outline and letter, 1981 (Folder 21)
  - "The Ground We Stand On: Democratic Humanism," Free Inquiry, Galleys, printed copy, and correspondence, 1982-1988, Winter 1981. (Folder 22)
  - "A Secular Humanist Declaration," Free Inquiry, (co-author with others). Printed copy, Winter 1981 (Folder 23)
  - Letter to the editor, American Spectator, Jan. 1981. Reply to comments by Paul Gottfried and Frank O'Connell on Hook's review of Norman Podhoretz's book The Present Danger. Typescript, printed copy, and typescript and printed copies of letters by Gottfried and O'Connell, 1980-1981 (Folder 24)
  - Review of Stanley Moore, Marx on the Choice between Socialism and Communism, Russian Review, Printed copy, Jan. 1981. (Folder 25)
  - Letter to the editor, New America, Relates to comments by Otto Nathan on Hook's article "Trotsky: The Prophet Who Failed." Typescript, printed copy, typescript and printed copies of Nathan's comments, and letters by Albert Einstein and Lewis Feuer, 1937-1981, Jan.-Feb. 1981. (Folder 26)
  - "The Autonomy of Moral Judgment," Free Inquiry, Contribution to the symposium "The Secular Humanist Declaration: Pro and Con." Printed copy, Spring 1981. (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - "The Classics of Secular Humanism," Free Inquiry, Contribution to a symposium. Printed copy, Spring 1981. (Folder 2)
  - "A Critique of Conservatism," National Forum, Printed copy and letters, 1981, Spring 1981. (Folder 3)
  - "Misrepresentation," New York Times, Letter to the editor relating to comments by Alfred Kazin on communism in education. Typescript, printed copy, and printed copy of Kazin's comments, 1981, April 12, 1981. (Folder 4)
  - "How Exclusive Should Humanists Be?" Free Inquiry, Response to Karl Popper. Typescript, galleys, and letter, 1981, Summer 1981. (Folder 5)
  - "'The Future Danger,'" Commentary, Letter to the editor relating to comments by Norman Podhoretz on world politics. Printed copy, Aug. 1981. (Folder 6)
  - "Jacobo Timerman," New York Times, Letter to the editor relating to the review by Anthony Lewis of a book by Jacobo Timerman. Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Leo Cherne, Jeane J. Kirkpatrick, Walter A. Sheldon and others, 1981, Aug. 2, 1981. (Folder 7)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Relates to disarmament. Typescript, Aug. 10, 1981 (Folder 8)
  - "Communism and the American Intellectuals from the Thirties to the Eighties," Free Inquiry, Printed copies, typescript letter to the editor by Lawrence Cranberg, and clipping, 1981-1982, Fall 1981. (Folder 9)
  - "To the President of Amherst College," Measure, Printed copy, Fall 1981. (Folder 10)
  - "So Schoen War's Frueher Mal in Kalten Kreig," Die Welt, Typescript (in English), printed copy, and letter, 1981, Sept. 12, 1981. (Folder 11)
  - "The Worldly Ways of John Kenneth Galbraith," American Spectator, Oct. 1981. Review of John Kenneth Galbraith, A Life in Our Times. Notes, holograph (incomplete), printed copy, and letters by Galbraith and others (Folder 12)
  - "General Education in a Free Society," Speech, Pepperdine University, Malibu, California. Holograph and letters, 1981-1982, Oct. 10, 1981. (Folder 13)
  - "A Million Dollar Gift's Forbidding Proviso," New York Times, Letter to the editor relating to endowment of a chair for a black professor at Amherst College. Printed copy, correspondence, press release, and clipping, 1981, Oct. 10, 1981. (Folder 14)
  - "More on Amherst's Cross Chair," Boston Globe, Letter to the editor. Printed copy and letter, 1981, Oct. 15, 1981. (Folder 15)
  - "Looking for Threats to the University in the Wrong Place," Holograph and letter, 1981, Oct. 24, 1981. (Folder 16)
  - "Human Rights and American Foreign Policy," Commentary, Contribution to symposium. Typescript, printed copy, and letter, 1981, Nov. 1981. (Folder 17)
  - "Books for Christmas," American Spectator, Short contribution. Printed copy, Dec. 1981. (Folder 18)
  - Letter to the editor, Free Inquiry, (date written). Relates to comments by Corliss Lamont on Hook's article "What the Record Shows." Typescript, printed copy of Lamont's comments, and correspondence with Lamont and others, 1982 (Folder 19)
  - "Pragmatismus und Marxismus," Prospectus, contract, and letters, 1982 (Folder 20)
  - "The Battle Continues," Measure, Holograph, typescript, printed copy, legal briefs, legal decisions, and letter, 1981, Winter 1982. (Folder 21)
  - "What the Record Shows," Free Inquiry, Relates to comments by Corliss Lamont on Hook's article "How Exclusive Should Humanists Be?" Typescript, galleys, printed copy, and galleys of Lamont's comments, 1981, Winter 1982. (Folder 22)
  - "Lukacs Hooked," American Spectator, Reply to comments by John Lukacs on Hook's article "The Worldly Ways of John Kenneth Galbraith." Typescript, printed copy, typescript and printed copies of Lukacs' comments, and correspondence with William F. Buckley, Jr., John Kenneth Galbraith and others, 1981-1982, Feb. 1982. (Folder 23)
  - "A Call for the Critical Examination of the Bible and Religion," Free Inquiry, (co-signer with others). Printed copy, Spring 1982 (Folder 24)
  - "Out of the Depths," American Scholar, Spring 1982. Review of Anton Antonov-Ovseyenko, The Time of Stalin. Typescript, printed copy, contract, and letter, 1981-1982 (Folder 25)
  - "Reflections on the Frankfurt School," Address, Marx Symposium, San Francisco. Typescript, agenda and list of participants, typescript copies of papers by other symposium participants, printed article, and notes, 1973-1982, March 1982. (Box 83, Folder 1-2)
  - "Soviets Won't Honor Freeze," Stanford Daily, Typescripts, printed copy, printed comments by Joe Walder, and letter, 1982, April 23, 1982. (Folder 3)
  - "Nuclear Freeze Talk Needs a New Focus," Peninsula Times- Tribune (Palo Alto, California), Interview. Printed copy, and letter by Tom Lantos, 1982, April 26, 1982. (Folder 4)
  - "Key Omission?" Stanford Daily, Letter to the editor relating to Hook's article "Soviets Won't Honor Freeze." Typescript and printed copy, April 30, 1982. (Folder 5)
  - "Rights for Potential Crime Victims," Newsday, Printed copy, May 13, 1982. (Folder 6)
  - "Verifying a Nuclear Freeze," Stanford Daily, Reply to comments by Joe Walder on Hook's article "Soviets Won't Honor Freeze." Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Walder and another, 1982, May 13, 1982. (Folder 7)
  - "My Running Debate with Einstein," Commentary, Printed copy, and correspondence with Martin F. Herz, Flora Lewis, Jay Lovestone, John Stachel and others, 1982-1983, July 1982. (Folder 8)
  - "The Nuclear Freeze," Freedom at Issue, Printed copy, July-Aug., 1982. (Folder 9)
  - "A Dissent on Kohrmon," Brattleboro [Vt.] Reformer, Letter to the editor relating to disarmament. Typescript, printed copy, and letter, 1982, Aug. 4, 1982. (Folder 10)
  - "An Interview with Sidney Hook at Eighty," Free Inquiry, Printed copy, and correspondence with G. Merle Bergman, Brand Blanshard, Theodore Draper, and Addison Potter, 1982-1983, Fall 1982. (Folder 11)
  - "The First Amendment vs. the Rest of the Constitution," Denver Post, Printed copy, Sept. 26, 1982. (Folder 12)
  - "The Causes of Cold War," Television broadcast. Holograph, transcript, and letter, 1982, Oct. 25, 1982. (Folder 13)
  - "Living with Deep Truths in a Divided World," Speech, 80th birthday dinner for Sidney Hook, New York City. Holograph, proofs, printed copies, and letters by Daniel P. Moynihan and others, 1982-1983, Oct. 29, 1982. (Folder 14)
  - "Einstein," Commentary, Letter to the editor relating to comments by Otto Nathan on Hook's article "My Running Debate with Einstein." Holograph, printed copy, and typescript and printed copies of Nathan's comments, 1982, Nov. 1982. (Folder 15)
  - "The American Committee for Cultural Freedom," Commentary, Letter to the editor relating to comments by Stephen Siteman on Hook's article "My Running Debate with Einstein." Holographs, typescripts, proofs, printed copy, printed excerpt, typescript and printed copies of Siteman's comments, and letters from William Phillips and Norman Podhoretz, 1982, Dec. 1982. (Folder 16)
  - "The Soviet Threat to Peace and Freedom," Washington Times, Typescript and printed copy, Dec. 9, 1982. (Folder 17)
  - "A Symposium: The Bishops and the Arms Race," New York Times, One of several contributors. Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence with Martin E. Marty, Dennis Paulson and another, 1982-1983, Dec. 26, 1982. (Folder 18)
  - "A Comment on Professor Goldman's Paper," Holograph and typescripts, 1983. (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Foreword to Paul Hollander, The Many Faces of Socialism: Comparative Sociology and Politics, Holograph and proofs, 1983. (Folder 2)
  - Marxism and Beyond, 1983. Typescript, contract, printed excerpts, reviews, and correspondence with Stuart E. Colie and others, 1982-1984 (Folder 3)
  - Open telegram to Yuri Andropov, 1983 (co-signer with others). Relates to the attempted assassination of Pope John Paul II. Typescript and clipping, 1982-1983 (Folder 4)
  - Preface to Roy Godson, Disinformatzia, Typescript, 1983. (Folder 5)
  - Letter to the editor, San Francisco Chronicle, (date written). Relates to comments by Jacobo Timerman on Israel. Typescript, Jan. 14, 1983 (Folder 6)
  - "Karl Marx versus the Communist Movement," Free Inquiry, Printed copy, Spring 1983. (Folder 7)
  - "Ominous Rumblings in the Academy," Measure, Typescript and printed copy, March 1983. (Folder 8)
  - "What is at Stake in the Existence of NATO?" Times (London), (date written). Typescript and letter, 1984, March 1983 (Folder 9)
  - "Second Thoughts on an Important Distinction," Speech, Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, Washington, D.C. Notes, holograph, and typescript, March 8, 1983. (Folder 10)
  - "Statement Concerning the Disruption of the Thomas Jefferson Lectureship at Berkeley," Proposed open letter (to be co-signed with others). Typescript, clippings, and correspondence with Peter Gay, Ira Michael Heyman, Jeane J. Kirkpatrick, and J. R. Pole, 1983, March 15, 1983. (Folder 11)
  - "Human Rights and Foreign Policy," Speech, 11th Annual George S. Counts Lecture, Southern Illinois University, Carbondale. Notes, holographs, brochures, clipping, and correspondence, 1983, April 21, 1983. (Folder 12)
  - "What Is Living and Dead in Karl Marx?" Lecture series, Sonoma State University, Calif. Notes, holograph (incomplete), brochure, and letters, 1983, April 27-28, 1983. (Folder 13)
  - "Edging towards Disaster?" Measure, Typescript and printed copy, May 1983. (Folder 14)
  - "What Can Be Done?" Measure, Holograph and printed copy, May 1983. (Folder 15)
  - Letter to the editor, [Southern Illinois University] Daily Egyptian, (date written). Relates to news coverage of Hook's speech "Human Rights and Foreign Policy." Typescript, May 2, 1983 (Folder 16)
  - "The Morality of Survival in a Nuclear Face-Off," Los Angeles Times, Printed copies, May 11, 1983. (Folder 18)
  - "The Test Is Always the Quality, Not Quantity, of Scholarly Works," [Stanford University] Campus Report, Open letter to President Donald Kennedy of Stanford University. Printed copy, clipping, and letter by Kennedy, 1983, May 11, 1983. (Folder 19)
  - "Partisanship at Stanford: Are Hoover's Critics Applying a Double Standard?" Peninsula Times-Tribune, (co-author with Edwin Harwood). Typescript, May 14, 1983 (Folder 20)
  - "Sidney Hook Interview," Free Inquiry, Letter to the editor relating to comments by Edwin H. Wilson on "An Interview with Sidney Hook at Eighty." Holograph, typescript, printed copy, and typescript and printed copies of Wilson's comments, 1982-1983, Summer 1983. (Folder 21)
  - "Is 'Color Blindness' Stupidity?" Typescripts, June 2, 1983. (Folder 22)
  - "An Open Letter to the U.S. Senate," Washington Times, Printed copy, July 26, 1983. (Folder 23)
  - "Cold Warrior: An American Appreciation," Encounter, Relates to Arthur Koestler. Typescript, printed copy, and letter by Melvin J. Lasky, 1983, July-Aug. 1983. (Folder 24)
  - "How to Build Democracy in a Developing Country," Speech, Taipei, Taiwan. Typescript, printed copy, and clipping, 1983, Nov. 1983. (Folder 25)
  - "The Incredible Story of Michael Straight," Encounter, Printed copy, reviews by Noel Annan, Hugh Trevor-Roper and others, and correspondence with Albert Glotzer and others, 1983-1984, Dec. 1983. (Folder 26)
  - Letter to the editor, Chronicle of Higher Education, (date written). Relates to proposed Ronald Reagan Library and the Hoover Institution. Typescript, Dec. 14, 1983 (Folder 27)
  - "American Committee for Cultural Freedom," Typescript, ca. 1984. (Folder 28)
  - Review of Elinor Langer, Josephine Herbst, Holograph note relating to the Hiss-Chambers affair, ca. 1984. (Folder 29)
  - "Pluralistic Societies at Stake," in Joseph Godson, ed., Challenges to the Western Alliance, Printed copy, 1984. (Folder 30)
  - "The Politicization of the University," in John H. Moore, ed., To Promote Prosperity: U.S. Domestic Policy in the Mid-1980's, 1984. Typescripts, printed copies, contract, and letter, 1982-1984 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - "The Philosopher as a Young Man," New York Times, Jan. 29, 1984. Review of The Collected Papers of Bertrand Russell, Vol. I, Cambridge Essays, 1888-99. Typescript, printed copy, and letters (Folder 2)
  - "Breaking with the Communists: A Memoir," Commentary, Printed copy, Feb. 1984. (Folder 3)
  - "Judging Brecht," Times Literary Supplement, Relates to comments by John Willett on Bertolt Brecht. Typescript, printed copy, and printed copy of Willett's review, 1984, Feb. 3, 1984. (Folder 4)
  - Letter to the editor, Harper's, (date written). Relates to U.S. participation in NATO. Typescript and letter, 1984, Feb. 24, 1984 (Folder 5)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Feb. 27, 1984. Relates to the New Leader and Sol Levitas. Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "Bertrand Russell: A Portrait from Memory," Encounter, Printed copy, comments by Kenneth Blackwell and others, and correspondence with Kenneth Blackwell, Robert E. Faris, Melvin Lasky and another, 1984, March 1984. (Folder 7)
  - "Memories of the Moscow Trials," Commentary, Printed copy and letter, 1984, March 1984. (Folder 8)
  - "Rights for Victims," Banner (Cleveland, Tennessee), Printed copy, March 5, 1984. (Folder 9)
  - "Judging Brecht," Times Literary Supplement, Reply to response by John Willett to Hook's article "Judging Brecht." Printed copy, and proofs of reply by Willett, March 9, 1984. (Folder 10)